Guide to the Arthur Lee Loeb papers M1590
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
Arthur Lee Loeb papers,
circa 1940s-2002
M1590
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
54.75 Linear feet (105 manuscript boxes, 3 cartons, 2 card boxes, 4 oversize flat boxes)
Papers of Arthur Lee Loeb contain correspondence, publications, presentations, textbooks related primarily to chemistry, faculty papers, material related to M.C. Escher, juvenalia, photographs, etc.
Loeb, Arthur L.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given by the Estate of Charlotee I. Loeb to Stanford University, Special Collections in 2007.
Biographical note
Arthur Lee Loeb was a scientist and crystallographer who was born in Amsterdam, the Netherlands on July 13, 1923 and died in Cambridge, Massachusetts in 2002.
Loeb was an internationally renowned leader in the field of design science. Throughout his career, he successfully combined the worlds of science and art, devising a language of spatial patterns that he described as "Visual Mathematics." He arrived in America in 1940 after fleeing his native Holland on the first day of the Nazi occupation. He was admitted to the University of Pennsylvania at the age of 20 and went on to earn his Ph.D. in chemical physics from Harvard in 1949. His scientific career began while working on the Whirlwind computer project, in which scientists at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (M.I.T.) struggled to develop "core memory" for the next generation of computers. It was at M.I.T. that Loeb began to articulate a language of spatial patterns that became the central focus of his career, leading to lifelong collaborations with such innovators as R. Buckminster Fuller and M.C. Escher.
Loeb was a founder of the International Society for the Interdisciplinary Study of Symmetry (ISIS-Symmetry), used to be its first Vice-President, later Chairman of the Advisory Board, until 2001. [From the Harvard Gazette and Wikipedia]
Scope and Contents
The papers have been minimally processed and arranged in 10 series: Series 1. Correspondence, Series 2. Publications, Series 3. Faculty/Coursework, Series 4. MC. Escher, Series 5. Miscellaneous, Series 6. General files, Series 7. Associations/Conferences/Bulletins, Series 8. Academic Juvenalia, Series 9. Born-Digital Materials, and Series 10. Oversize materials.
Series 1, Correspondence, is arranged in two alphabetical sequences.
Series 2, Publications, consists primarily of articles and books by Arthur Loeb, but includes some by Buckminster Fuller and others.
Series 3, Faculty/Coursework, primarily relates to the Harvard University Visual and Environmental Studies Department. It includes correspondence, committees, curriculum review, exhibisitions, Task Forces and reports, lectures, etc.
Series 4, M.C. Escher, is primarily related to Loeb's collaborations with Escher and contains correspondence with Escher and his widow, books, exhibition announcements, postcards, and some of Loeb’s essays on Escher.
Series 5, Miscellaneous, contains punch cards (alphabetical list of references), notebooks from Legdemont Labs, files related to dance (see also "medieval misc." in Series 6), Loeb's memorial, notes of Bucky Fuller, video interview with Loeb on survivors on the holocaust, etc.
Series 6, General Files, relate to Loeb's varied interests such as medieval era, art, and contain photographs of Loeb and his work. The folders titled “medieval misc.” contain files on medieval and renaissance dances as Loeb was interested in the symmetry and repeating patterns.
Series 7, Associations/Conferences/Bulletins, contains materials primarily related to the American Crystallographic Association.
Series 8, Academic Juvenalia, contains a diary from 1940, schook notebooks, papers, textbooks, etc.
Series 9, Born-Digital Materials, are CLOSED until processed.
Series 10, Oversize Materials, consist of paste-ups for Loeb's books and articles as well as photographs of his models.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy. Series 10. Born-Digital Materials is CLOSED until data is fully accessioned and processed.
Selected Bibliography
Fuller, R. Buckminster, and E. J. Applewhite. Synergetics: Explorations In the Geometry of Thinking. New York: Macmillan, 1974.
Harris, Louis, and Arthur L Loeb. Introduction to Wave Mechanics. New York: McGraw-Hill, 1963.
Kepes, Gyorgy. Module, Proportion, Symmetry, Rhythm. New York: G. Braziller, 1966.
Loeb, Arthur L. Color and Symmetry. New York: Wiley-Interscience, 1971.
Loeb, Arthur L. Concepts & Images: Visual Mathematics. Boston: Birkhäuser, 1993.
Loeb, Arthur L. The Electrical Double Layer Around a Spherical Colloid Particle: Computation of the Potential, Charge Density, and Free Energy of the Electrical Double Layer Around a Spherical Colloid Particle. Cambridge: Massachussetts Institute of Technology, 1961.
Loeb, Arthur L. A n Interionic Attraction Theory For Regions of Solutions Near Phase Boundaries and An Analysis of Langmuir’s Theory Of Repulsion Between High Potential Surfaces In A Solution. Harvard University, 1949 [thesis]
Loeb, Arthur L. Space Structures: Their Harmony & Counterpoint. Reading: Addison Wesley, 1976; Boston: Birkhäuser, 1991.
Malina, Frank J. Visual Art, Mathematics and Computers: Selections From the Journal Leonardo. Oxford: Pergamon, 1979.
Senechal, Marjorie and George Fleck. Shaping Space: A Polyhedral Approach. Boston: Birkhäuser, 1987 [series editor preface]
White, Alvin M. Interdisciplinary Teaching. San Francisco: Jossey-Bass, 1981.
Wrinch, Dorothy, and Marjorie Senechal. Structures of Matter and Patterns In Science: Inspired by the Work and Life of Dorothy Wrinch, 1894-1976. Cambridge, Mass.: Schenkman, 1980.
Applewhite, E. J.; Edmonson, Amy C.; Escher, M.C. (Maurits Cornelis),, 1898-1972; Estate of Charlotte I. Loeb.; Fuller, R. Buckminster (Richard Buckminster), 1895-1983; Kepes, Gyorgy, 1906-2001; Lima-de-Faria, J. (José), 1925-; Senechal, Marjorie; Skinner, B. F. (Burrhus Frederic), 1904-1990; Swirnoff, Lois; Chemistry.; Crystallography, Mathamatical; Crystals--Structure; Harvard University--Environmental Studies; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945)--Personal narratives; Mathematics, Design; Mathematics--Philosophy.; Photographs.; Symmetry (Physics); Synergetics; System theory
- Series 1: Correspondence
  Scope and Contents
  Series 1, Correspondence, is arranged in two alphabetical sequences.
  - Correspondence: Campbell. Ted (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Cambridge Center for Adult Education (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Cambridge School Volunteers (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Cambridge University, 1 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Cambridge University, 2 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Caris, Gerard (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Casale, Ralph (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Cass, Dr. Leo J. (Harvard) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Chemical Engineering News (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Chorbachi, Wasma'a (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Christensen, Prof. C. Roland (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Clapp, Philip C. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Columbia University (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Columbia Pacific University (Scott Talkington) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Commission on Crystallographic Teaching (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Convair Corp. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Consulting (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Donnay, J.D.H. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Dreher, Dennis (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Dunitz, Jack D (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Dupont Co. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Ealing Corp. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Emmer (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Emmerich, D. G. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Encyclopedia Americana (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Engineering, American Society for Engineering Education (ASEE) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Epstein, Robert (1 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Epstein, Robert (2 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Epstein, Robert (3 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Epstein, Robert (4 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Fine Print & Arion Press) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Fullmer, V.A. (MIT Vice-President) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Gabriel, Jean Francois (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Gabriel, Jean Francois (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Gabriel, Jean Francois (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Geodestix (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Getty Grant Program (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Gold, Dr. Louis (clean coal), 1 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Gold, Dr. Louis (clean coal), 2 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Graetz, Claudia Hall Windisch (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Green, Prof. Edward J. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Group of 63 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Grubaum, Banko (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Hahn, Prof. Theo (Aachen, Germany) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Hall, William L. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Hargattai, Istvan, Fivefold Symmetry/Symmetry I (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Hargattai, Istvan, Symmetry II (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Hargattai, Istvan, Computers & Mathematics (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Harvard University, Computer Aided Graphics (1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Harvard University, Computer Aided Graphics (2 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Harvard University, Computer Aided Graphics (3 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Harvey, Walter W. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Hatfield, Prof. Robert (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Haughton, Eric (1 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Haughton, Eric (2 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Haughton, Eric (3 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Hecker, Zvi (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Henisch, Heinz K. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Hellner, Prof. Erwin (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Hiigli, John A. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Holser, William T. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Howling, Dennis H. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Komoski, Dr. Kenneth Center for Programmed Instruction (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: London Times (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Loreto, Lucio (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - McGraw-Hill:Intro to Wave Mechanics, correspondence 1957, 1958, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - McGraw-Hill: Intro to Wave Mechanics, correspondence 1960, 1961, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - McGraw-Hill: Intro to Wave Mechanics, correspondence 1963, 1964, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - McGraw-Hill: Intro to Wave Mechanics, correspondence 1966 on (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - McGraw-Hill: Intro to Wave Mechanics, corrections, additions etc. to me (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - McGraw-Hill: misc. reviews, brochures, etc. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - McGraw-Hill: Symmetry program, Loeb & Haughton (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Moduledra: miscellaneous correspondence (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Moduledra: ads, drawings, sketches, papers, etc. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Moduledra: ads, catalogs, papers, etc. from other sources (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Moduledra: exhibit at AAPT (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Moduledra: Lynn-Sign Plastics and Metaloglass (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Moduledra: trademark (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Moduledra: Therodyne, brief history of (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Moduledra: orders for supplies (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Machlin, Prof. Eugene (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: MacKay, Alan (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Maller, Alexander (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Manchester Bicknell Company (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Maruyama, Magorah (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Mindel, Joseph (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: MIT Press (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Morris, Larry (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: New York Academy of Science (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: New York Academy of Science (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Niggli, Prof. Alfred (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Nordby, Prof. Gordon, Univ. Of Michigan (Box 7)
  - Correspondence: Projects, collaboration (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Projects, misc. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Randle, Jay W. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Re, Paul (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Reed, Dr. Thomas B., Lincoln Laboratory (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Reeves, E. Duer (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Reggini, Prof. Horacio C. (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Reinhold Publishing Co. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Richards, Isabelle (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Robbins, Martin (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Robinson, Charles D. (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Robinson, Charles D. (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Robinson, Wade M. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Robinson, Lawrence Baylor, Space Technology Lab (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Robertson, William D. Yale University (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Rockefeller Foundation (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Rosenbaum, Albert (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Rowan, Julian (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Royal Society of Art (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Russell, Beverly (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Hrand Saxenian Associates (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Scatchard, Prof. George (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Schoen, Dr. Alan H., NASA (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Science (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Scientific American, Science Museum (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Segal, Gerry, Project Synergy (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Stewart, Duncan (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Symmetry (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Von Stetten, Carl (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Wiese, Epi (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Willow, Diane (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Wilson, Prof. A.J.C. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Van't / Adam 1951-1959 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Van't / Adam 1960-1964 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Van't / Adam 1965- (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Van't / Adam publications & technical reports (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Verheten (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Vinsani, Mario, Olivetti (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Von Hippel, Prof. A. R (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Wainwright, William H. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Walter, Marion (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Walkup, Lewis E., Batelle (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Wechsler (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Wenniger, Magnus (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Whirlwind I (laboratory/bldg.) (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: White, Alvin (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Whyte, Lancelot L. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: John Wiley & Sons Ltd. Publishers (1 of 4) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: John Wiley & Sons Ltd. Publishers (2 of 4) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: John Wiley & Sons Ltd. Publishers (3 of 4) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: John Wiley & Sons Ltd. Publishers (4 of 4) (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Wilson, Prof. M. Kent (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: University of Wisconsin (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Wittke, Prof. Oscar (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Wolfe, Prof. Caleb W. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Wolff, G.A., Tyco Labs (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Woodward, Eudora (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: World Institute (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: Wright, Vedder (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Yale University (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Zwarts, Moshe (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Zener, Clarence (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Zelweger (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: Odd correspondence (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: general (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: 1954-55 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, general & misc. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, general & misc. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, general & misc. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: Assorted EUI (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: Norbert J. Blum EUI (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: Richard Benesh EUI (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: Arthur Boutilier EUI (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: Lem Chastain EUI (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: Dorothy Cole re: Findhorn (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: Doron Chen EUI? (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: Shane Eversfield (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: Stuart Franklin (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: R. Ginsberg EUI (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: Pat Gunkel EUI "Ideonomy" charts (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: Joseph Raphael Mateo EUI? (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: Joseph Moore EUI (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, general & misc.: T. Woodrow Wilson EUI (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: general 1989-90 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: AHUJA, Mangho ts:"Calligraphic Tessellation of Ali" (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: ALDERMAN, Holly Compton (1 of 2) (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: ALDERMAN, Holly Compton (2 of 2) (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: ALLEN, Marytha (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: ARLINGHAUS, Sandra Loch (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: APPLEWHITE, E.J. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: ARNHEIM, Prof. Rudolf (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: BAKANOWSKY, Prof. Louis J. Dept. Chair VES (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: BALLANTYNE, J.M. (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: BALLANTINE BOOKS (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: BAR-HILLEL, Prof. Yehoshua (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: BALTZER, Dr. Philip K. (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: BERNARD, Michael M. (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: BOLT, Dr. G.H. (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: BORG, Andrew S. (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: BRISSON, David & Harriet (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: BROOKS, Lloyd O. American Institute for Research (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: BROWN, Harold (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: BUERGER, Martin J., M.I.T. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: BURNLEY, Roger L., University of Pennsylvannia (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: BUNT, Dr. Lucas (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: BURT, Prof. Michael, Technion-Israel (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: CORLISS, Dr. Lester M. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: CROMMELIN, Dr. R.D., Bennekom, Netherlands (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: DREHER, Dennis (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: EDMONSON, Amy (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: EDMONSON, Amy, "A Fuller Explanation " (1 of 2) (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: EDMONSON, Amy, "A Fuller Explanation " (2 of 2) (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: ENGEL, Peter (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: ERASMUS Lectureship (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Erasmus Lectureship (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: FLEISCHER, David (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: FULLER/LOEB (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Board of Director's Fuller Institute: Funding packet draft (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Board of Director's Fuller Institute (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Board of Director's Fuller Institute (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: re: Fuller retrospective film "INTUITION" (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: GOLD, Dan (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Honorary Degree (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: KENNER, Hugh (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: William Kronick Productions (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: LeCorbeiller, Prof. Philippe, Loose tables & charts (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: LeCorbeiller, Prof. Philippe, Symmetrical Subdivision of the Euclidean Plane (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: LeCorbeiller, Prof. Philippe, June/July 1967 re: monograph (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: LeCorbeiller, Prof. Philippe, memorial (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: LeCorbeiller, Prof. Philippe, rough drafts of papers (1 of 2) (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: LeCorbeiller, Prof. Philippe, rough drafts of papers (2 of 2) (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: LAPERLE, Philippe (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: LEONARDO Magazine (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous (Arthur Loeb's personal file) (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Micellaneous/General 1964-1968 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Micellaneous/General 1969-1973 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: National Society for Programmed Instruction (includes draft of "Programmed Use of Physical Models") (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: O'BEIRNE, Thos H., Glasgow, Scotland (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: OLDCHURCH, Ronald (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: PABST, Prof. A., University of California Berkeley (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Pan American Society of New England (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Pearce, Peter (1 of 2) (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: PEARCE, Peter (2 of 2) (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: PEARSON, William B., National Research Council of Canada (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Pennsylvannia State University (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Philadelphia College of Textiles and Science (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Philips Research Laboratories (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Physical Science Study Committee re: Logical Machines (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Princeton University Press (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Radcliffe College (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: RANDOLPH, P. Francis (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: RESNIKOFF, Howard L. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: ROBINSON, John G. (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: ROTTERDAM, Dr. Paul, Harvard Carpenter Center (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: St. Hippolyte, Michael de (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: SAYED, Hazem I. (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: SEKLER, Prof. Edward (1 of 2) (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: SEKLER, Prof. Edward (2 of 2) (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: SENECHAL, Marjorie (1 of 5) (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: SENECHAL, Marjorie (2 of 5) (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: SENECHAL, Marjorie (3 of 5) (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: SENECHAL, Marjorie (4 of 5) (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: SENECHAL, Marjorie (5 of 5) (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: SENECHAL, Marjorie, Smith College (1 of 3) (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: SENECHAL, Marjorie, Smith College (2 of 3) (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: SENECHAL, Marjorie, Smith College (3 of 3) (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Society for Industrial & Applied Mathematics (SIAM) 1953-1955 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: SIAM 1956-1960 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: SIAM 1966-1970 (Box 36, Folder 3)